Guide to the Nathaniel and Thomas Shaw Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Papers of Nathaniel and Thomas Shaw letters, accounts, bills, receipts, notes, orders, etc.
  - Ralph Pomeroy account - Adventure 4th voyage: Item Nos. 5069-5107, 1758-1781 (Box 13, Folder 88)
  - Sloop Sally, 1st - 6th voyage: Item Nos. 5108-5182 (Schooner, etc. 5156-5163, 5165-5167), 1757-1778 (Box 13, Folder 89)
  - Nathaniel Shaw Items
    - Item Nos. 5183-5227, 5229-5245, 5247-5261, 5263-5272, 5274-5275, 5277-5297, 5299-5306, 5309-5317, 5319-5330, 1768-1790 (Box 14, Folder 90)
    - Item Nos. 5332-5383, 1771-1778 (Box 14, Folder 91)
    - Accounts: Item Nos. 5384-5400, 5403-5407, 5410-5428, 5430-5434, 5436, 5441, 5455-5457, 5467, 5482-5485, 5502-5503, 5506, 5587-5589, 1782, etc. (Box 14, Folder 92)
  - Brig Nancy bills, accounts, orders, etc.: Item Nos. 5507-5573, 1777-1779 (Box 14, Folder 93)
  - Sloop Macaroni: Item Nos. 5578, 5580-5582, 5585-5587, 5590, 5593-5596, 5599-5600, 5602, 5604-5605, 5607-5613 1/2, 5615-5617, 5620-5623, 1775-1777 (Box 14, Folder 94)
  - Thomas Shaw Items
    - Writs: Item Nos. 5624-5783, 1780-1795 (Box 14, Folder 95)
    - Item Nos. 5784-5969, 1777-1794 (Box 14, Folder 96)
    - Bills, etc.: Item Nos. 5970-6091, (No number 6020), 1786-1794 (Box 15, Folder 97)
    - Letters, etc.: Item Nos. 6094-6161, 6163, 6165-6166, 6169-6173, 6175-6179 6181-6185, 6187-6209, 6211-6221, 6223-6235, 1772-1789 (Box 15, Folder 98)
    - Accounts, etc.: Item Nos. 6237 1/2 - 6336, 1791 (Box 15, Folder 99)
    - Letters: Item Nos. 6337-6342, 6345-6348, 6350-6367, 6370-6371, 1794 (Box 15, Folder 100)
  - Notes of little or no value: Item Nos. 6372-6455, 1761-1784 (Box 15, Folder 101)
  - David Greene and Hubbard & Greene: Item Nos. 6456-6489, 1782-1793 (Box 16, Folder 102)
  - M. Arseneau: Item Nos. 6520-6528, 1783-1784 (Box 16, Folder 103)
  - Thomas Shaw Items
    - Accounts: Item Nos. 6529-6594, 1781 (Box 16, Folder 104)
    - Item Nos. 6595-6614, 6616-6637, 6639-6660, 6662-6664, 1779-1791 (Box 16, Folder 105)
    - Accounts: Item Nos. 6665-6693, 1776-1784 (Box 16, Folder 106)
    - Letters: Item Nos. 6694-6748, 1786-1787 (Box 16, Folder 107)
  - Schooner Two Brothers Item. Nos. 6749-6765, 6767-6770, 6772, 6775-6776, 6780, 6783-6784, 6786-6788, 6791-6792, 6795, 1784-1792 (Box 16, Folder 108)
  - Thomas Shaw - J. Waters letters: Item Nos. 6800-6801, 6803-6805, 6807-6824, 6826-6828, 6830-6833, 1782 (Box 16, Folder 109)
  - Col. Josiah Waters' letters: Item Nos. 6834-6836, 6839-6861, 6863-6864, 1783 (Box 16, Folder 110)
  - E. Champlin's orders: Item Nos. 6865-6907, 1783-1792 (Box 16, Folder 111)
  - Thomas Shaw: Item Nos. 6908-7000, 7002-7025, 1770-1795 (Box 17, Folder 112)
  - Thomas Shaw: Item Nos. 7026-7172, 1762-1785 (Box 17, Folder 113)
  - American Revenue, 7th cruise: Item Nos. 7177-7195, 1777-1779 (Box 17, Folder 114)
  - Thomas Shaw Items
    - Letters: Item Nos. 7196-7220, 7222, 1789 (Box 17, Folder 115)
    - Item Nos. 7223, 7227-7228, 7230-7233, 7235-7249, 7251-7254, 1776-1793 (Box 17, Folder 116)
    - Bills, etc.: Item Nos. 7255-7327, 1790 (Box 17, Folder 117)
    - Accounts: Item Nos. 7328-7425, 1787 (Box 17, Folder 118)
    - Item Nos. 7426-7512, 7516-7518, 7520-7522, 7525-7556, 7558-7587, 7591, 7593-7600, 1776-1795 (Box 18, Folder 119)
    - Item Nos. 7601-7668, 1765-1788 (Box 18, Folder 120)
    - Item Nos. 7669-7674, 7676-7684, 7686-7687, 7689-7696, 7698-7702, 7704-7711, 7713-7741, 1776-1795 (Box 18, Folder 121)
    - Letters: Item Nos. 7742-7758, 7760-7836, 7844-7863, 7865, 7868-7891, 1764-1795 (Box 18, Folder 122)
  - John de Newville accounts, etc.: Item Nos. 7892-7956, 7958, 7964, 7967-7970, 1781-1795 (Box 18, Folder 123)
  - Thomas Shaw Items
    - Item Nos. 7977-7983, 7988, 7994, 8020, 8022, 2113, 1766-1793 (Box 19, Folder 124)
    - Accounts: Item Nos. 8064-8157, 1792 (Box 19, Folder 125)
    - Letters: Item Nos. 8158-8163, 8164-8175, 8178-8213, 1792-1793 (Box 19, Folder 126)
    - Item Nos. 8214-8267, 8269-8274, 8280-8324, 1770-1795 (Box 19, Folder 127)
    - Item Nos. 8325-8422, 1765-1789 (Box 19, Folder 128)
    - Bills, etc.: Item Nos. 8423-8473, 1795 (Box 19, Folder 129)
    - Item Nos. 8474-8476, 8480-8507, 1770-1795 (Box 19, Folder 130)
  - M. Melally accounts, etc.: Item Nos. 8508-8580 (No. 8545 not used), 1776-1792 (Box 19, Folder 131)
  - Adventure, 2nd voyage: Item Nos. 8587-8589, 8593-8594, 8599, 8601, 8605-8608, 8613, 8636, 8653, 8660, 8662, 8672, 8697-8704, 1756-1792 (Box 19, Folder 132)
  - Brig Nancy: Item Nos. 8687-8696 (Box 19, Folder 132)
  - Thomas Shaw Items
    - Item Nos. 8609, 8614-8615, 8617, 8623, 8630-8631, 8646, 8655, 8659, 8663-8666, 8668, 8674, 1776-1800 (Box 19, Folder 133)
    - Unnumbered letter, Sears & Smith to John Deshon-James Tilley, April 29, 1785: Item No. 8564, 9113-9114, 9116-9120, 9123-9173, 9176-9178, 9180-9182, 9187, 9189-9195, 9199-9203, 9206, 9208-9209, 9213, 9227, 9230-9235, 9237-9243, 9246-9248, 9252, 9254, 1776-1794 (Box 20, Folder 134)
    - Letters: Item Nos. 8711-8722, 8725, 1784-1785 (Box 20, Folder 135)
    - Receipts, orders, etc.: Item Nos. 8727-8756, 8758-8762, 8773, 1771-1801 (Box 20, Folder 136)
    - Item Nos. 8775-8781, 8783-8791, 8793-8795, 8797-8877, 8879-8789 8891-8903, 8905-8906, 8909-8912, 8914-8932, 1770-1795 (Box 20, Folder 137)
    - Notes, etc.: Item Nos. 8933, 8936-8940, 8942-8970, 1779-1786 (Box 20, Folder 138)
    - Letters: Item Nos. 8971-8974, 8975, 8978-8986, 8989-8995, 8998-9003, 1788 (Box 20, Folder 139)
  - Josiah Waters letters: Item Nos. 9005-9026, 1784 (Box 20, Folder 140)
  - Thomas Shaw: Item Nos. 9028, 9044, 9046, 9050, 9051, 9052, 9070, 9074, 9075, 9078, 1756-1778 (Box 20, Folder 141)
  - Sloop Macaroni, bills, first voyage: Item Nos 3103-3110 (Box 20, Folder 141)
  - Thomas Shaw: Item Nos. 9027, 9027-9043, 9045, 9048-9049, 9053-9054, 9056-9058, 9061-9069, 9071-9073, 9076-9077, 9080, 9082, 9084-9094, 1775-1788 (Box 20, Folder 142)
  - Isaac Wharton letters: Item Nos. 9095-9111, 1786 (Box 21, Folder 143)
  - Death of Nathaniel Shaw: Item Nos. 9172-9173, 9183-9185, 9197-9198, 9210, 1772-1785 (Box 21, Folder 144)
  - Schooner Two Brothers, etc.: Item Nos. 9258-9263, 9265-9266, 9271-9277, 9279-9288, 1777-1791 (Box 21, Folder 145)
  - Ship America, etc.: Item Nos. 9289-9342, 1771-1791 (Box 21, Folder 146)
  - Shaw vs. Stanton & Noyes: Item Nos. 9343-9345, 1777-1791 (Box 21, Folder 147)
  - Rhode Island and Providence Plantations: Item No. 9346, 1790 (Box 21, Folder 148)
  - Unnumbered items, not in inventory, 1762-1780
    - Macaroni - portage bill, 1775 (Box 21, Folder 149)
    - Macaroni - cargo, first voyage - sale (Box 21)
    - Macaroni - cargo, first voyage - powder (Box 21)
    - Resistance - Capt. Chew's account (Box 21)
    - Protest, 1763 (Box 21)
    - Endeavor - Estimates (Box 21)
    - List of men of Col. Lippett's Regiment, etc. (Box 21)
    - Deserted from Oliver Cromwell (Box 21)
    - Account, Prize Ship True Blue (Box 21)
    - Officers & Seamen, American Revenue (Box 21)
    - List of men, Brig Resistance (Box 21)
    - Charty Party, Schooner Industry (Box 21)
    - Brig Favourite account (Box 21)
    - Brig Hampton account (Box 21)
    - Brig Cabbot receipt (Box 21)
    - Ship Trumbull account (Box 21)
    - Ship Putnam (Box 21)
  - Transcripts of letters made by the Department of State for Nathaniel Shaw Perkins in 1900: (Box 21, Folder 150)
    General
    15 Letters from Nathaniel Shaw to General Washington; Letters from F. Greene to General Washington; Letters from Nathaniel Minor to Governor Trumbull; Letter from Nathaniel Shaw to Governor Trumbull; Letter from Esek Hopkins to Nathaniel Shaw; 2 letters from Governor Trumbull to President Hancock; Letter to Governor Trumbull from Thomas Shaw and others.
  - Accounts
    - Ledger no. 1, of accounts with customers, 1772-1795 (Box 25)
      Scope and Contents
      This was kept in conjunction with ledger no. 25. These two volumes with a few pages of accounts in no. 2 constitute the customer accounts of Shaw's mercantile business, 1765-1797. There are entries p.216 for settlement of the estate of the widow Ann Ledyard, 1791. (1 vol. - 40x26 cm.)
    - Ledger no. 2, 1790-1799 (Box 26)
      Containing 30 p. of entries recording debits and credits for services including some for farming; one p. of receipts, 1796-1799, for interest on a note from John A. Lawrence due the estate of Thomas Shaw. Most of the volume is blank. (1 vol. - 38x23 cm.)
    - Ledger no. 3 in two parts, 1778-1779, 1777-1795 (Box 25)
      The first part deals with the sale of clothing and cloth goods, with off-setting credits for shares in mercantile ventures sponsored by Shaw; and entries for supplying the ship General Putnam. The magnitude of some of the transactions is indicated by the accounts with Capt. Nathaniel Saltonstall and Amaziah Joicelin pp. 71, 72. In inverse and reverse order there are lists of articles removed from, date of capture of, destination of, and list of men left in charge of, the prizes Surprise, Joseph, Princess Royal, Dispatch, Elizabeth, and Carolina.
      The second part contains 5 pp. of an inventory (probably that of a ship's cargo); a list of notes and secruties held by Shaw, giving date, number, and in whose favor drawn; a list of securities given "soldiers in the Connecticut Line"; a list of Continental Loan Certificates; underwriting accounts showing rate, gains and losses on total premiums, adjusted premiums, vessels' name, makers' name, destination, and payee. (1 vol. - 48x26 cm., sewed in loose paper cover)
    - Ledger no. 4, of mercantile accounts, 1756-1780 (Box 26)
      Including inventories of cargoes shipped, entries for the outfitting, supplying, and financing of various ventures, and 7 pp. of accounts of the building and outfitting of the sloop American Revenue. Cargoes shipped by Shaw included staves, shingles, headings, hay, meat, fresh vegetables, candles, horses, fowl, etc. There are accounts for the prize ship La Jean Teresa, 1757 [see Record no. 40], and entries concerning the estate of Josiah Rogers, 1761. More than half the pages are blank. (1 vol. - 37x14 cm.)
    - Ledger no. 5, describing the mercantile business of the Shaw's in account form, 1765-1780 (Box 26)
      The accounts are arranged alphabetically by customers with place of residence often indicated, and show sales of wheat, bread, meal, oats, sugar, salt, tea, butter, turnips, onions, beans, beef, mutton, veal, vinegar, molasses, rum, brandy, wine, flannel, oil, indigo, yarn, shingles, staves, planks, nails, iron, shovels, spades, axes, marine hardware, supplies, etc.
      There are a few credit entries indicating the purchase of hay, sugar, brandy, rum, molasses, peas, corn, and beef; also constant references to a "Ship Book", probably kept in conjunction with this ledger; annual property lists, 1768-1781, of Nathaniel and Thomas Shaw; and three pages of accounts with Nathaniel Shaw, Sr. (1 vol. - 31x16 cm., sewed in heavy paper cover)
    - Ledger no. 6, of accounts of the sloop, 1779 (Box 22)
      Kept by the captain, William Leeds, listing officers and crew, articles of clothing to the latter, charges for food and services to the ship, and expenses incurred in disposing of the prize ships Nancy, Dispatch, and Polly, and their cargos.
      There are copies of five letters from Capt. Leeds to Patrick Moor, probably an owner, written from Basse Terre, Guadaloupe, describing privateering activities of the sloop in this region and giving information on the French and British fleets in these waters under D'Estaing and Byron, respectively. (1 vol. - 26x20 cm., sewed in paper cover)
    - Ledger no. 7, 1776-1781 (Box 22)
      Accounts of sale of marine supplies and services to vessels; maintenance and preparation for sale of prize vessels; 80 pages for the sale of cloth and cloth goods; and entries for the disposition of the prize vessel Polly. Accounts concerning the prize vessels Arthol, Mary, Two Brothers, Sally, and Polly are found throughout the ledger, as are those for the ships American Revenue, Sampson, and Fair American. (1 vol. - 28x18 cm., sewed in paper cover)
    - Sales ledger no. 8, undated (Box 22)
      Recording sales of contents of numbered boxes, trunks, tierces, etc., presumably a ship's cargo. The first 26 pages are a continued list of articles sold, purchaser, and price, apparently recorded as each trunk or cask was opened.
      The next 37 pages are a record of these sales at vendue, arranged by purchasers, with an index to the names in back of volume.
      There is one page near the end of the volume headed "The Owner of the Sloop American Revenue 6th Cruise". Showing net proceeds "of the Prizes sold in West Indies" and of other ventures of this cruise. It is not clear that the preceding entries relate to this ship, but the allusion to prizes indicates the Revolutionary period. (1 vol. - 32x20 cm., sewed in paper cover.
    - Ledger no. 9, 1777-1778 (Box 22)
      Describing the outfitting of various warships, including the Cabot, American Revenue, Defense, Revenge, and Oliver Cromwell. There are charges for processing the prize ships John, Sally, and Clarendon; and a list of sale at "Public Vendue" of coffee from the prize True Blue; also, an account with the [Connecticut] Colony for military supplies. Miscellaneous customer accounts appear throughout. (1 vol. - 28x18 cm., sewed in paper cover)
    - 9 folio pages [no. 12], undated (Box 22)
      Recording the disposition of the cargoes of the prize ship Putnam, and the ships Nancy, Clinton, and Charming Nancy, whose status is not clearly indicated. Some of the foods were given over directly to the Board of War, while the others were sold at auction and the proceeds distributed to owners and crew. An interesting account of the charges for disposition can be found on the last two pages. (1 vol. - 25x18 cm., uncovered)
    - Ledger no. 13, 1755-1757 (Box 22)
      Entries for the sale of foodstuffs, hardware, and cordage. Cordage is bartered for yarn and meats. (1 vol. - 20x16 cm., lacking cover)
    - Ledger no. 14, 1757-1758 (Box 22)
      Concerning the sloop Sally, the prize schooner, St. Ann, and her capturer, the sloop Blakeney. Sales of the prize cargo of the St. Ann show amounts of each commodity, purchaser of same, and price; followed by record of sales arranged by purchasers, with credits to some for shares in the prize. Records of the sale of the privateer sloop Blakeney show purchasers, items purchased, and cost; followed by record of sale arranged by purchasers, with credits to those owners shares in the sloop. The last 4 p. are entries for the sloop Sally on her first, second and third voyages. (1 vol. - 23x19 cm., sewed in paper cover)
    - Record no. 16, 1777 (Box 22)
      Listing weights of cargoes of a prize taken by the ship American Revenue, and a prize taken by both the ships American Revenue and United States. The disposition of the proceeds to crew and owners is carefully computed. The weight of a shipment of hogsheads of sugar shipped for Messrs. Grilling and Dickson is recorded. Shaw deducted 12 per cent of the cargo for "fares", and recorded the dale of this cargo. Most of the pages are blank. (1 vol. - 32x21 cm., sewed in paper cover)
    - Pocket account book no. 18, of Elias Perkins, 1786-1788 (Box 22)
      Elias Perkins (1767-1845, Yale 1786), lawyer of New London, Conn., who married Lucretia Shaw Woodbridge, granddaughter of Nathaniel Shaw, Sr. Entries are not numerous and are for personal and legal matters. On last page are entries showing that Perkins boarded with Justice Oliver Ellsworth, from Nov. 1786 to some time in 1788, during which time he probably read law under Justice Ellsworth. Filed with Elias Perkins Papers (1 vol. - 17x10 cm., bound in paper)
    - Record no. 21, 1777-1782 (Box 22)
      Containing entries for personal accounts, records of Continental, State, and personal notes held by Shaw, and various records of legislation giving insight into the procuring, financing, and maintaining of the local and state militia. Near the middle of volume is "a Continental scale of depreciation of money". There is a page entitled "Connecticut Quota of Supply" listing various amounts of beef, salt, hay, and rum, followed by a list of "Prices [for foodstuffs] that each State are to Charge". (1 vol. - 17xl0 cm., lacking cover)
    - Ledger, no. 25, 1765-1783 (Box 28)
      Of accounts with customers. Sales include those of wheat, meal, oats, bread, sugar, salt, rice, cinnamon, molasses, rum, tobacco, coffee, brandy, wine, vinegar, chocolate, butter, pork, beef, mutton, veal, fish, onions, turnips, beans, corn, oil, indigo, yarn, flannel, linen, cloth, articles of clothing, hides, shingles, staves, planks, boards, cordage, tar, pitch, calking, nails, iron, shovels, spades, axes, marine hardware and supplies. The origin of many of these goods is indicated in the contra or credit accounts with each customer. (1 vol. - 30X24 cm.)
    - Ledger no. 26, 1776-1779, 1796-1804 (Box 22)
      Consisting mainly of entries describing Shaw's activities in the Revolutionary War. There are charges for the outfitting of the ships Defense, Oliver Cromwell, Trumbull, Resistance, etc.; for war supplies to the forts Trumbull, Griswold, and Stonington; to the State of Conn.; to Col. Woolcot's Regiment, stationed at New London; to the Hon. Marine Committee [the last on p. 100-106, 129]; and to the Continental Navy Board [p.131]. There are several pages of accounts headed "Espenses of Flags to New York", describing expenses incurred in sending prize vessels to New York, and transporting prisoners to New York and to various forts.
      Removed from this volume is an inventory and appraisal of the estates of Lynide and Richard Manwaring of Waterford, Conn., n.d., but not before 1825. (1 vol. - 32x20 cm.)
    - Ledger and daybook no. 27, 1779-1795 (Box 23)
      Recording sales of the usual goods and produce. The first 118 pp. are customer accounts, many of which contain little more than the account heading. Nearly half of the book is devoted to daybook entries, 1781-1795.
      In back volume there are: six p. of "Duties Received", 1790-1794; a list of "Disposition of Certificates", 1789; and, in reverse and inverse order, lists of the capture of the prizes Hunter, Polly, Liberty, Nancy, Charming Nancy, Clinton, Showing their date of capture and goods removed fromand prizemaster and crew left with same. A folio sheet, "Roll of the Officers and Men belonging to the Sloop American Revenue July 1778", was removed from this book. From other account books in this collection it is clear that the American Revenue shared in the disposition of these prizes; therefore it seems likely that the lists in no. 27 describe this shop's very active privateering record.
      There are 60 blank pages in this book, the first 34 pp. are missing, and the binding is in poor condition. (1 vol. - 33x20 cm.)
    - Ledger no. 28, 1771-1795 (Box 23)
      Of accounts with customers for sale of the usual and produce dealt in by the Shaws. There are accounts with Peter Vandervoort, Thomas and Isacc Wharton, and Hubbard & Greene, jobbers for Shaw in New York, Philadelphia, and Boston, respectively. These transactions indicate the great amount of business done by Shaw. There is an account, 1775, with Joseph Trumbull, p. 43; several with the Town of New London; and charges for a 5 per cent commission from the sale of various cargoes, plus duties paid, wharfage, piloting, etc. There is an index of customers in the front.
      Removed from this volume was a memorandum, probably by Thomas Shaw, concerning charges of Peter Mumford against the estate of Nathaniel Shaw. Undated but not before 1792. (1 vol. - 30x19 cm.)
    - Ledger no. 29, 1770-1785 (Box 28)
      Of customer accounts, indicating sales of rum, sugar, tea, molasses, tobacco, brandy, corn, pork, beef, fish, salt, chocolate, boards, nails, articles of clothing, hides, etc. Index in front. (1 vol. - 40x16 cm.)
    - Daybook no. 30, 1775-1778 (Box 27)
      Describing sale of commodities indicated in no. 29 above. (1 vol. - 40x16 cm.)
    - Ledger no. 31, 1778-1779 (Box 23)
      Accounts for sale of beef, sugar, coffee, and shares in mercantile ventures. Off-setting credits for customer's share in realized ventures are frequent. Near the end of volume are 2 pp. describing the disposal of the cargoes of the prizes Hunter and Polly to owners and crew, containing a list of owners and their respective shares in the capture. There is an index at the end. (1 vol. - 38x12 cm., sewed in newspaper)
    - Daybook no. 32, 1778-1792 (Box 28)
      Recording fees charged for legal services, including pleading of cases in court, settling of financial disagreements, and claims, and serving summonses, etc. (1 vol. - 42x13 cm., lacking cover.)
    - Daybook no. 33, 1779-1781 (Box 28)
      Entries for sale to individual customers and vessels of rum, wine, beef, pork, fish, sugar, salt, chalk, tallow, nails, cordage, powder, etc. (1 vol. - 40x16 cm., sewed in paper cover)
    - Ledger no. 34, 1778-1780 (Box 24)
      Accounts dealing with the maintenance and supply of privateers operated by the government, the State of Connecticut, and Shaw; with the care of "Sick Prisoners from New York" (12 p.); charges for materials and labor on the ships Le Despencer, Nancy, American Revenue, Defense, General Putnam, Oliver Cromwell, Trumbull, Elliot, and Pompey; and charges for dockage, storage, and legal expenses incurred in the disposition of the prizes Polly, Berkley, Hazard, Sally, and Dove. (1 vol. - 37x26 cm., sewed in paper cover)
    - Record no. 35, 1777 (Box 24)
      The sale at public vendue of the brigantine Sally and cargo (a prize of the ship American Revenue ), including a list of all items sold, their purchasers, and price; and an account of all legal expenses and of the settlement with the owners. (1 vol. - 32x20 cm., covered in paper)
    - Ledger no. 36, 1756-1778, lacking entries for 1763-1775 incl. (Box 24)
      In the front of the volume are three pages of lists, 1758-1762, of vessels grounded, or captured by the British or French, their masters, destination, and the average loss incurred by underwriters on their shares of cargo; and in inverse and reverse order in back of volume, 14 p. of "Premiums received", 1756-1767, listing vessels, their masters, underwriters, destination, and the insurance rate charged on specified sums. Accounts, 1776-1778, record charges to various customers and off-setting credits to some on shares in mercantile ventures. Eight pages are devoted to the disposition of prizes taken by the ship American Revenue in 1777, including a list of sales at vendue with the customers designated for each item by lot. (1 vol. - 32x20 cm., sewed in paper cover)
    - Volume no. 37, 1733-1791 (Box 24)
      Consisting of several different records, including: 10 p. listing lands acquired, 1733-1791, by Nathaniel Shaw, Sr, and Jr., and Thomas Shaw, giving names of persons from whom acquired; 9 pp of "commissary Proceedings", 1781-1784, describing the administration of prisoners placed in Shaw's care, including charges to the "United States" for his services: in inverse and reverse order, charges, 1777, incurred in the disposition of the prizes Two Brothers, Mary, Athol, Rebecca, Sally, Carolina, and Sheelah; and records, 1776-1779, of the 6th and 7th cruises of the privateer, American Revenue. (1 vol. - 32x21 cm., sewed in paper cover)
    - Record no. 38, 1769-1777 (Box 24)